RYAN TSE

Electrical Engineering and Math Student



@ rytse@umd.edu



College Park, MD









Electrical engineering and math student interested in novel applications of "pure" math to engineering problems, particularly in control theory, machine learning, and digital signal processing (DSP). Graduating with a combined B.S./M.S. in Spring 2023. Previously worked on radar DSP at Nuro, a self-driving delivery vehicle startup. Currently developing a robust, geometry-inspired reinforcement learning alternative tailored to multi-agent control problems with funding from New Science.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Intern (Radar)

Developed, simulated, and implemented digital signal processing algorithms for radars on self-driving delivery vehicles.

Intelligent Automation Incorporated

Intern (Communications, Localization)

June 2019 – August 2019 Rockville, MD

Assisted in the hardware implementation of a bursty space-time continuous phase modulation receiver by analyzing quantization error. Assisted in developing indoor positioning system technology by modifying tracking filters to include IMU data.

Naval Research Laboratory

Intern (Communications)

May 2018 – August 2018

Washington, DC

Developed an efficient bursty satellite ranging protocol in GNURadio. Applied control loops to correct for channel impairments and implemented packet protocols.

Naval Research Laboratory

Intern (Localization)

■ June 2017 – August 2017 Washington, DC

Applied deep learning to vehicle trilateration.

TOOLS



EDUCATION

University of Maryland

B.S. + M.S. in Electrical Engineering, B.S. in Mathematics

Aug 2019 – Present

Select Completed Courses

(star indicates graduate level course)

- Advanced Calculus
- Partial Differential Equations
- Differential Forms
- Abstract Algebra *
- Systems Theory *
- · Communications Systems
- Controls Lab

- Optimal Control *
- Optimization for Control *
- Random Processes *
- Advanced Digital Signal Processing *
- Stochastic Control *

Select Current Courses:

- Nonlinear Control *
- · Estimation and Detection Theory *

PROJECTS

Computationally Approximated Manifold Control

Independent Research

March 2021 - Present

College Park, MD

Inventing a robust, geometry-inspired reinforcement learning alternative tailored to multi-agent control problems. Funded by New Science. Details and paper coming soon.

Auto-Drifter

Hackathon Project

April 2022 - Present

College Park, MD

Designing a model-predictive control (MPC) law to autonomously drift a car in VDrift. Solved LQR on a linearized model for the short-time optimal control. Working through a numerical instability in linearization. Plan to eventually implement direct multiple shooting on the nonlinear model.

blair3sat

Team Founder, President, and RF Instrument Engineer

2017 – 2019

Rockville, MD

Developed a CubeSat to measure 3D ionospheric charge density profiles by receiving ground-based ionospheric sounders from space. Designed DSP algorithms for the instrument and lead the team in spacecraft engineering and fund seeking in an executive capacity. Secured \$6,000 of funding and two corporate partnerships in 6 months. Co-wrote conference presentation for SmallSat 2019.